The birth of boxing.
Prizefighter: The Life of Jem Belcher is a history,
drama film directed by Daniel Graham.
At the turn of the 19th century, Pugilism was the sport of kings and a gifted
young boxer fought his way to becoming champion of England.
Jem Belcher, played by Matt Hookings.
Bill Warr, played by Ray Winstone.
Mary Belcher, played by Jodhi May.
Lord Rushworth, played by Marton Csokas.
Jack Slack, played by Russell Crowe.
Walter, played by Steven Berkoff.
Prizefighter: The Life of Jem Belcher is a 2022 British-American biographical drama
film about the birth of boxing, written by and starring Matt Hookings.
The film explores the life of Jem Belcher who became
the youngest ever world champion.
Jem was partially blind at the age of 22 and dead by the age of 30.
The film stars Matt Hookings as Jem Belcher, Ray Winstone as his trainer Bill
Warr and Russell Crowe as Jem's boozy grandfather Jack Slack.
Marton Csokas, Jodhi May, Steven Berkoff, Julian Glover,
Julius Francis are the supporting cast.
The film was first theatrically released in Russia on June 30, 2022, and
it had a VOD release by Amazon Prime on July 22, 2022.
The tone is emotional.